# NICHOLAS SAMEER BARR

#### CONTACT

**Phone:** 778-834-3160

Email: nickbarr100@gmail.com

**WWW:** https://nickbarr.ca/

#### **EDUCATION**

**Diploma**: Digital Design And Development, 04/2022 **British Columbia Institute of Technology** - Burnaby, BC

**1st & 2nd Year**: Computer Science, 04/2020 **University of Western Ontario** - London, ON

High School Diploma, 06/2018 High School, Heritage Woods Secondary School - Port Moody, BC

#### **SKILLS**

- Public Speaking
- Strong interpersonal skills
- · Effective communicator
- · Proven leadership capability

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

As a BCIT graduate with a solid academic background and leadership roles in sports, I've spent just under two years in the front-end development industry. I'm eager to further explore and seize opportunities in this dynamic field.

#### WORK HISTORY

### Software Developer, 04/2022 to 09/2023 Mellenger Interactive - Vancouver

- Conducted security enhancements and routine maintenance for several WordPress and Drupal Platforms
- Crafted various UI components in React for multiple websites.
- Discussed issues with team members to provide resolution and apply best practices.
- Participated in software field testing to verify performance of developed projects.

### **Digital Marketing Manager and Web Developer,** 09/2020 to Current **Kinder Kampus Children's Services**

- Redesigned old website to improve responsiveness, accessibility, search optimization by 40% and aesthetics
- · Managing digital marketing on Google and Facebook
- Administration support, configuration and commissioning of tablet computers for playing music, video, photos, internet access, and MS word applications at five local childcare centres in Port Moody, BC.

### Front End Developer, 09/2021 to 12/2021 BuzzyBee

- Managed full-cycle design tasks, handling phases from conception to completion while maintaining guidelines throughout.
- Completed page components
- Designed a fully responsive user interface
- Developed an algorithm to receive and restructure data using a custom rest API for the front end

### Full Stack Developer, 01/2021 to 05/2021

- Managed development milestones from initial steps through final delivery.
- · Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues.
- Developed page components
- Designed fully responsive user interface

### **House Detailing Technician,** 04/2020 to 08/2020 **Shack Shine**

- Completed window washing, gutter cleaning and pressure washing of high end residential homes
- Organized and managed equipment, including a Mercedes Sprinter
- Worked with clients to provide exceptional customer service
- Invoiced and completed payments

## **Customer Service,** 05/2017 to 08/2019 **Westwood Plateau Golf And Country Club**

• Welcomed guests, coordinated special events and tournaments, managed golf cart fleet, and assured customer satisfaction at executive golf club in Coquitlam, B.C.

### Materials Management, 06/2015 to 08/2017 Creative Children Education Supply

• Materials management, packaging, distribution and order fulfillment at educational materials supplier in Port Moody, B.C.